Guide to the Anne Brigman Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Anne Brigman papers
1914-1947
YCAL MSS 380
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2.91
(6 boxes)
Contains photographs, writings, and printed material documenting the work of Anne Brigman. Included among the papers are four paste-up copies of Brigman's book of photography and poetry, Songs of a Pagan and one paste-up copy of her second book, Wild Flute Songs. The papers also contain early typescript drafts of Songs of a Pagan, clippings on Brigman, exhibition notices and flier, and other printed material.
Brigman, Anne, 1869-1950
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Anne Brigman (1869-1950)
Anne Brigman, photographer and poet. She was among the original members of the Photo-Secession movement.
Scope and Contents
The Anne Brigman Papers contain photographs, writings, and printed material documenting the work of Anne Brigman. Included among the papers are four paste-up copies of Brigman's book of photography and poetry, Songs of a Pagan and one paste-up copy of her second book, Wild Flute Songs. The papers also contain early typescript drafts of Songs of a Pagan, clippings on Brigman, exhibition notices and flier, and other printed material.
American poetry -- 20th Century; Poets -- 20th Century; Photography, Artistic; Photography -- 20th Century; Photographs; Photographers; Brigman, Anne, 1869-1950; Photo-Secession (Association)
- Songs of a Pagan, undated (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Paste-up of book, with some or all of the photographs used and some or all of the typescript poems, signed. Linen covered boards.
- Songs of a Pagan, 1939 (Box 2)
  Paste-up of book, with some or all of the photographs used and some or all of the typescript poems, signed.
- Songs of a Pagan, 1946 (Box 3)
- Wild Flute Songs, 1946 (Box 4)
  Paste-up of book, with photographs used and some or all of the typescript poems, signed.
- Vanity Fair, clipping of photographs by Brigman, 1914 June, 1916 June, 1918 June; 3 (Box 5)
- San Francisco Examiner, "New Trail in Art Blazed by Woman," article about Brigman, 1924 December (Box 5)
- Camera Craft, frontispiece is "Invictus" by Anne Brigman. Also contains "The Glory of the Open" (illustrated) by Brigman., April 1926 (Box 5)
- "Bulletin of the Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences", 1932 April 2 (Box 5)
- San Francisco Brigman exhibition notice, undated (Box 5)
- Puck, clipping of photographs by Brigman, undated (Box 5)
- Songs of a Pagan, typescript drafts, corrected, 1919, undated; 2 (Box 5)
- Songs of a Pagan, paste-up with typescript drafts of poems, undated (Box 5)
- Songs of a Pagan, publicity flier, undated (Box 5)
- "Extra photographs to illustrate Brigman, Songs of a Pagan, received back from the Los Angeles Engraving Company", circa 1947 (Box 6)